eudora.com 2001-12-11

# Eudora Privacy Statement

| 

**Eudora Privacy Statement**

**QUALCOMM has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website,[WWW.EUDORA.COM](http://www.eudora.com/), and for our Eudora email client when it is in Sponsored mode.**

**

Eudora will never share information about you without your permission (unless required by law). 

WEB SITE: www.eudora.com

**

> IP addresses of visitors to our Web site are used to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. IP addresses are also used to compile general demographic information. We will not attempt to identify individual users through their IP addresses.
> 
> Our website uses cookies. Cookies are used to make sure users don't see the same ad repeatedly as well as to deliver content specific to users' interests.
> 
> **Order Forms  
>  **Our site uses an order form for customers to request information and services and purchase products. We collect visitors' contact information (like their names and email addresses). In the event the customer is making a purchase, we will also require additional financial and billing information (like credit card, shipping address, telephone, etc.). Contact information from the order form is used to ship orders. Users may opt in and grant their permission for us to use their contact information to send them information about our company and promotional material from some of our partners. Users may opt out of receiving future mailings at any time.
> 
> **Surveys**  
>  Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like their names and email addresses). With the user's permission, we use contact data from our surveys to send the user information about our company, products and promotional material. If the user chooses to allow us, we may also send mail with special offers from our sponsors. 
> 
> With the user's permission, demographic and profile data (like zip code, age or income level) is also collected from our surveys. We aggregate this information eliminating personally identifiable information in the process. The aggregate information is shared with advertisers. We will not share personally identifiable information without the user's permission.
> 
> We will also use this information to tailor the offers we make to users who have given us permission, but we do not link users' personal contact information to the general demographic information we collect. Users may opt in to receiving information or opt out of receiving future mailings. 

**EUDORA Desktop Email Client.**

> Eudora 4.3 or greater running in Sponsored mode, Light mode or Paid mode, whether purchased in a retail store or downloaded electronically, regularly contacts QUALCOMM update servers to check if newer versions of Eudora are available. If a newer version is available, Eudora will notify the user and give the user the option to upgrade. The user has the ability to disable the update check at any time. Instructions for disabling this feature can be found at eudora.com for [Windows](http://www.eudora.com/techsupport/kb/2111hq.html) and [Mac](http://www.eudora.com/techsupport/kb/2122hq.html) versions of the software. The program also checks to see whether the logo of a co-branding affiliate should appear in the Light and Sponsored modes. No personal information whatsoever is transmitted back to QUALCOMM during these processes. 

**EUDORA 4.3 Sponsor-supported Email Client Software**

> **Registration Information  
>  **When a user registers, we collect certain contact information (like email address and first and last name) that will be used to verify the user's eligibility for services and upgrades, provide services like technical support and verify a user's identity in the case of a lost registration code. This information may also be used to contact the user, with their permission. 
> 
> **Ad-specific Information  
>  **In order to operate properly, the sponsor-supported version of Eudora 4.3 collects certain information (like current operating system, monitor bit depth and size, version and mode of Eudora, Eudora use time). This information is used to meet our requirements to our sponsors and to serve content that looks good and is appropriate and compatible with users' systems. We also collect data on what ads users currently have on their computer. This is used to manage ad traffic and help tech support and our web administrators to solve any problems. If the software detects a problem with displaying ads, it warns the user. The warning includes a button that can be clicked by the user to ask for the problem to be diagnosed. Should the user specifically ask to have the problem diagnosed, information about failed attempts to receive ads will be transmitted to us. This information is also useful in determining what areas of the program need enhancement. 
> 
> From time to time, some of Eudora's advertising will only be applicable to certain geographic regions (phone services, insurance providers, etc). In such cases, Eudora will use the user's IP address to send the most appropriate advertising. Many IP addresses are commonly associated with Internet service providers, universities, or major corporations in specific regions or localities. The only information used in this procedure is the data about the geographic region from which the user's computer is contacting the Internet. Absolutely no personal information (email address, address of residence, demographics, etc.) is revealed to QUALCOMM or our advertisers in these situations.
> 
> **Other Information  
>  **We also collect, from a small percentage of users who have authorized us to do so, information on Eudora usage (like features used) and Internet connection time. **This does not contain actual data entered by the user. Any identifying information gathered is immediately separated from this information, so that we have no idea whose usage pattern we have.**
> 
> **User Profile  
>  **When users fill out a demographic profile, a profile ID is generated and sent to the Eudora client software on the user's system. This information is used to serve ads that are more relevant to the user. The user can choose to modify or delete the profile at any time.

**Eudora 5.0 Sponsor-supported Email Client Software**

> **User Profile  
>  **Users of version 5.0 will be required to complete, after a short trial period, a demographic survey in order to continue using the software in Sponsored mode. The first time the software is run, a profile ID is generated and sent to the Eudora client software on the user's system. If the user chooses not to complete the profile, the software will revert to Light mode at the end of the trial period. The user has the option, at any time, to pay for the software in which case advertising will be removed and a survey is not required. A user in Light mode may switch to Sponsored mode at any time by filling out a profile. This demographic information is used to serve ads that are more relevant to the user. The user can modify the profile at any time. 
> 
> We aggregate this information eliminating personally identifiable information in the process. The aggregate information is shared with advertisers. We will not share personally identifiable information without the user's permission.
> 
> **We will never, for any purpose whatsoever, examine the contents, addresses, subjects or attachments of user emails. This is true of all other data users enter in their address book, personalities, filters, stationery, etc.**

**Updates to this Privacy Statement  
**While we will never change our fundamental commitment to protecting user privacy, regulatory changes or other circumstances may require us to modify this Privacy Statement. In the event that we do amend this Statement, we will post the amended Statement on our website at http://www.eudora.com/privacy, and the amended Statement will be effective 15 days after it is first posted. 

**Contacting the Web Site  
**If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact our [webmaster.](mailto:webmaster@qualcomm.com)

Last updated 10/10 2000
